<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Needle in the Hay</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Needle in the Hay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing squashinformr: Politely web scrape data from SquashInfo in R</title>
      <link>/introducing-squashinformr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/introducing-squashinformr/</guid>
      <description>A Project Salvaged  Earlier this year, I enrolled in a Data Management course as a part of my MSc in Business Analytics. The final project in this course involved writing a business case study, designing a database model, and building a MySQL database. As a squash enthusiast, I chose to base my project on the Professional Squash Association (PSA). The business case was that if the PSA invested in a database, they could enrich the viewing experience for PSA TV subscribers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five R tips from my Voices.com internship</title>
      <link>/code-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/code-tips/</guid>
      <description>1. Removing similarly-named objects from R’s Global Environment2. coord_cartesian() for zooming in on ggplots3. Intra-figure legends in ggplot2 graphics4. High resolution plot outputs via CairoPNG()5. Fuzzy joins on intervals with genome_left_join()Conclusion This summer, I had the pleasure of working as a Data Analyst Intern at Voices.com as a part of my MSc in Business Analytics. Voices.com is a marketplace website that matches business clients with voice-over talent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hmdrmd: R Markdown templates for data analysis</title>
      <link>/hmdrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/hmdrmd/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown R Markdown1 is a powerful R package that allows users to dynamically render their work (code, graphs, and text) into various file formats. Its wide range of outputs (including HTML, PDF, Word) makes it one of the most flexible and intuitive communication tools within the R community. Ultimately, R Markdown bridges the gap between data professionals and the audience they need to communicate to. In fact, I’m communicating to you right now through an R Markdown document rendered to HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston 2018</title>
      <link>/tufte-and-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/tufte-and-viz/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended Edward Tufte’s course, “Presenting Data and Information”, in Boston. I learned about the course through twitter after reading about Tufte, who is a professor emeritus of political science and statistics at Yale. As a future business analytics student, I was very interested in a one day course taught by a data visualization expert. The most enticing factor was that it seemed to be the most design-focused course that I had read about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case Against Young Link</title>
      <link>/hbox-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/hbox-bayes/</guid>
      <description>Melee! Super Smash Bros. Melee for the Nintendo GameCube was released in 2001. Since then, it has become one of the most adored games of the last twenty years. The game features many characters from various Nintendo game franchises, which players choose between before entering a match. The objective of each match is relatively simple: fight your opponent(s) and hit them beyond the boundaries of the stage. In contrast to fighting games, each time a player is struck they gain percentage points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Hayden MacDonald and I am a Canadian graduate student studying at Ivey Business School, University of Western Ontario.
Currently, I am pursuing a career in data analytics through Ivey Business School&amp;rsquo;s MSc in Business Analytics (expected graduation May 2020).
My interests include research, statistical data analysis, data visualization, technology, and marketing analytics.
In my spare time, I enjoy cooking, hiking, cycling, SCUBA diving, birding as well as watching films and eSports.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>