<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Needle in the Hay</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Needle in the Hay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston 2018</title>
      <link>/tufte-and-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/tufte-and-viz/</guid>
      <description>I recently travelled to Boston to attend Edward Tufte’s one day course, “Presenting Data and Information”. I learned about the course through twitter and later did some reading about Tufte, who is an esteemed professor emeritus of political science and statistics at Yale and previously taught with John Tukey. As a future business analytics student, I was interested in taking a convenient one day course taught by a world expert in data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case Against Young Link</title>
      <link>/hbox-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/hbox-bayes/</guid>
      <description>Melee! Super Smash Bros. Melee for the Nintendo GameCube was released in 2001. Since then, it has become one of the most adored games of the last twenty years. The game features many characters from various Nintendo game franchises, which players choose between before entering a match. The objective of each match is relatively simple: fight your opponent(s) and hit them beyond the boundaries of the stage. In contrast to fighting games, each time a player is struck they gain percentage points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Canadian graduate student studying at the University of Western Ontario.
In August 2018, I achieved a Master of Science in Psychology. Currently, I am transitioning to a career in data analytics through Ivey Business School&amp;rsquo;s MSc in Business Analytics (commencing January 2019).
My interests include research, statistical data analysis, and data visualization.
In my spare time, I enjoy cooking, hiking, cycling, SCUBA diving, birding as well as watching films and eSports.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>