<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Needle in the Hay</title>
    <link>/tags/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Needle in the Hay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing squashinformr</title>
      <link>/introducing-squashinformr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/introducing-squashinformr/</guid>
      <description>A Project Salvaged Earlier this year, I enrolled in a Data Management course as a part of my MSc in Business Analytics. The final project in this course involved presenting a business case for a database and building a MySQL database as a solution. As a squash enthusiast, I chose to base my project on the Professional Squash Association (PSA).
Long story short, I did not complete this project because it was cancelled due the spread of COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hmdrmd: R Markdown templates for data analysis</title>
      <link>/hmdrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hayden.macdonald.8778@gmail.com (Hayden MacDonald)</author>
      <guid>/hmdrmd/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown R Markdown1 is a powerful R package that allows users to dynamically render their work (code, graphs, and text) into various file formats. Its wide range of outputs (including HTML, PDF, Word) makes it one of the most flexible and intuitive communication tools within the R community. Ultimately, R Markdown bridges the gap between data professionals and the audience they need to communicate to. In fact, I’m communicating to you right now through an R Markdown document rendered to HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>